uopeople.edu 2019-05-26

# 

                                 University of the People Privacy Policy
Policy number:            04022016
Effective date:           May 25th, 2018
Last reviewed date:       May 21st, 2018
Owner:                    General Counsel
Summary:                 This policy governs the collection of personally identifiable
                        information through the University of the People website.
Policy Statement
University of the People is committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with this privacy
policy, which applies to the University of the People website, its related websites, and content
therein ("Website") as well as the services available through this Website ("Services"), and
governs collection of personally identifiable information through the website.
PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY. By using the website, you give your consent to
University of the People’s data practices and understand that all personally identifiable
information that you submit may be processed by University of the People in the manner and for
the purposes described herein.
If you do not agree to the terms and conditions set forth herein, do not use the website.
Collection of Personal Information
To apply for admission to University of the People (“UoPeople”, or the “University”), you must
submit personally identifiable information to the UoPeople website (“Website”). “Personally
identifiable information” ("PII") refers to data that allows University of the People to identify you,
such as your name, gender, mailing address, telephone number, date and country of birth,
government-issued identification number, e-mail address, and other personal information.
If you submit personally identifiable information through any of UoPeople’s Communications
Services (as described in the University’s Terms of Use), that information may be collected and
used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Information and How We Use It
By submitting your PII to the Website, you understand and agree that UoPeople may collect, use,
transfer, and disclose your personally identifiable information as described in this Privacy Policy.
The Website may collect, process and use the data which includes PII, the legal basis of which is
your consent, which you give when you use the Services. Types of PII that may be used include
the following, without limitation:
                                                   1

• We may process data about your use of our Website and Services ("User Data"). User
  Data may include your IP address, location, type of browser and version, operating
  system, referral source, visit length, page views and website navigation paths, as well as
  information about the frequency and timing of your use of the Service. The source of the
  User Data is an analytics tracking system. User Data may be processed for the purposes
  of analyzing the use of the Website and Services, operating our Website, improving and
  customizing the Services, ensuring the security of our Services, maintaining back-ups of
  our databases and communicating with you.
• When registering or inquiring on our Website you may be asked to enter your name,
  email address, mailing address, telephone number, email address, gender, date of birth,
  or other details ("Entered Data"). You are the source of such account data, and such data
  may be processed for the purposes of operating the Website, providing the Services,
  ensuring the security of the Website and Services, maintaining back-ups of our databases
  and communicating with you. The UoPeople will use your Entered Data for internal
  purposes including, but not limited to, academic and financial advising, record-keeping
  and tracking.
• We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding
  Services ("Enquiry Data").
• We may process information relating to transactions that you enter into with us and/or
  through our Website, such as the purchasing of goods ("Transaction Data"). The
  Transaction Data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction
  details. The Transaction Data may be processed for supplying the purchased goods and
  Services and keeping records of transactions.
• We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our
  email notifications, offering you services, or promotions which may interest you
  ("Notification Data"). The Notification Data may be processed for the purposes of
  sending you relevant Notification Data.
• We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you
  send to us ("Correspondence Data"), for example, when you sign up for our newsletter or
  respond to a survey or remarketing communication. The Correspondence Data may
  include communication content and/or metadata associated such communication. The
  Correspondence Data may be processed for communicating with you and record-
  keeping.
• We may process any of the types of data described in this Privacy Policy if we are
  required to do so by court-order, any legal obligation to which we are subject, or when
  necessary, for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. The legal basis for
  this processing is our legitimate interests, namely of the Website's legal rights, your legal
  rights and the legal rights of others.
                                            2

      •  Please do not supply any other person's PII to us without the specific and explicit consent
         of all parties, including the owner of such PII.
International transfers of your PII
In this Section, we provide information about the circumstances in which your PII may be
transferred to countries inside and outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").
You acknowledge that PII submitted by you for publication through the Services may be available
around the world via the internet. We cannot prevent the use or misuse of published PII by
others once you submit it for publication, nor are we liable for such third-party use or misuse.
Such use may involve transfer of personally identifiable information to servers located outside the
country from which you access the Website.
We and our other group companies have facilities in The United States, the Middle East, and
India. "Adequacy decisions" of the European Commission have been made with respect to the
data protection laws of each of these countries.
Transfers to countries inside and outside the EEA will be protected by appropriate safeguards,
namely the provisions of applicable law which relate to the protection of individuals with regards
to the processing of PII to which a party may be subject including, without limitation, the Data
Protection Act 1998, the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC, the Regulation of Investigatory
Powers Act 2000, the Telecommunications (Lawful Business Practice) (Interception of
Communications) Regulation 2000, the Electronic Communications Data Protection Directive
2002/58/EC, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and,
where applicable, the guidance and code of practice issued by the Information Commissioner’s
Office from time to time, directions of any competent regulatory authority, relevant regulatory
guidance and codes of practice (collectively “Data Protection Regulation”) or to the extent
transfers will cross borders to outside the EEA, such transfer shall be carried out in accordance
with standard contractual clauses annexed to the EU Commission Decision 2010/87/EU of 5
February 2010 for the Transfer of Personal Data to Processors established in Third Countries
under the Directive (the “Model Clauses”).
The hosting facilities for our Website are situated in The United States and Europe. The European
Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of
these countries. If you have opted-in and knowingly subscribe to our newsletter or other forms
of correspondence, we may also use your information to inform you of new services UoPeople
will be providing, inform you of scholarship applications and academic programs provided by
third parties, and send you requested information and promotional materials for marketing
purposes and research.
Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information
                                                   3

The University automatically collects non-personal information about your computer hardware
and software for the purpose of improving the administration and content of the Website,
facilitating use of the University’s Website by its users, and to properly diagnose server problems
and other issues.
The University may contract with third party providers to assist in better understanding visitors to
the Website. Third party providers are prohibited from using any information they collect on
behalf of UoPeople for any purpose other than helping the University conduct and improve its
services to you.
Information Sharing
The University does not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to third parties
without your prior written consent. Personally identifiable information collected in connection
with applications for admission is, however, collected by a third-party service provider that hosts
the Website, and that information is released to application reviewers who may include
University employees, contractors, volunteers and other parties. These individuals are prohibited
from using your personally identifiable information except in connection with UoPeople services
and any other products and/or services you have requested, and they are required to maintain
the confidentiality of your information.
UoPeople may disclose your personally identifiable information, without notice, (i) if required to
do so by law, or (ii) in the good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to protect or defend the
rights, system, network, property or personal safety of the University, its personnel or its
students. UoPeople may disclose your personally identifiable information, with prior notice,
subject to your consent, to a potential or actual partner or buyer in connection with a merger,
acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of the University’s assets.
The University requires opt-in consent (meaning, your express permission) to share any sensitive
personally identifiable information, such as medical information or information concerning race
or ethnicity, political or religious beliefs, and sexuality.
Your Rights
In this Section, we have done our best to summarize the rights that you have under data
protection law. These are complex, and not all of the details have been included herein. In light
of this, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full
explanation of these rights.
Your principal rights under data protection law are:
(a)      the right to access;
(b)      the right to rectification;
(c)      the right to erasure;
(d)      the right to restrict processing;
(e)      the right to object to processing;
(f)      the right to data portability;
                                                     4

(g)     the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
(h)     the right to withdraw consent.
You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and,
where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That
additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of
personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and
freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first
copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.
You can access your personal data by visiting the UoPeople Self-Service Portal when logged into
the website.
You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into
account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you
completed. UoPeople will also correct, amend or delete any personal information that is
inaccurate and notify any third-party recipients of the necessary changes. UoPeople may decline
to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate
technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is
not otherwise required by local law or GDPR.
In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data [by providing
adequate evidence attesting to your identity] without undue delay. Those circumstances include:
the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected
or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; the processing is for
direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. There are
certain general exclusions of the right to erasure. Those general exclusions include where
processing is necessary: [for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for
compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims].
In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those
circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you
oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you
require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have
objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been
restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only
otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal
claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of
important public interest.
You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your
particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the
processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the
exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued
by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal
information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which
                                                    5

override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise
or defense of legal claims.
To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is consent, and such
processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data
from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does
not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws,
you have a legal right to file complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data
protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work
or the place of the alleged infringement.
To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you
have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of
processing before the withdrawal.
You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us in
addition to the other methods specified in this Section 5.
Opt-in
When you provide us with PII for a secondary reason, like marketing or other secondary reasons
which we will convey to you from time to time if applicable, we will ask for your consent. After
you opt-in, you may withdraw your consent anytime, by contacting us at support@UoPeople.edu
or admissions@UoPeople.edu. Or, please go to this site to withdraw your consent to processing.
Security of your Personal Information
The University maintains reasonable measures to protect your personally identifiable information
from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. The University stores the personally identifiable
information you provide on computer servers in a controlled environment that has implemented
protections against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. UoPeople has implemented
procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not
limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have
been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of the Website as
part of University’s continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the
electronic transmission of information.
For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of the Website for all users, the
University employs software to monitor traffic and identify unauthorized attempts to upload or
change information or otherwise damage the Website. When personally identifiable information
(such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of
encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.
The University, however, cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to
defeat the measures described in this section or use your personally identifiable information for
improper purposes. Nothing in this Privacy Policy or in the University's Terms of Use shall be
                                                   6

deemed a guarantee, contract, or warranty of any kind, whether express or implied, regarding the
security of your personally identifiable information.
Educational Records
The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) of 1974 was designed to protect the
privacy of educational records, establish the rights of students to inspect and review their
educational records, and provide guidelines for the correction of inaccurate or misleading
information through informal and formal hearings. While FERPA does not apply to the University,
since it is not a federally-funded institution, the University nonetheless strives to meet FERPA’s
provisions to the extent reasonably feasible.
The University will not disclose a student's educational record without obtaining the student's
prior written consent, except that a student's educational record may be disclosed (i) to other
school officials, including teachers with a legitimate educational interest and contractors,
consultants, volunteers, or other parties to whom UoPeople has outsourced educational or
institutional services or functions; (ii) to parents of a dependent student, as defined in section 152
of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; (iii) to accrediting organizations; (iv) in compliance with a
judicial order or lawfully issued subpoena; or (v) for any other reason permitted under 34 CFR §
99.31.
The University depends on the accuracy of the records submitted by its students. False
information on an application, or any other act to intentionally mislead or misinform instructional
personnel or administrators, is grounds for disciplinary action, including dismissal from the
University. Students seeking access or amendment of their educational records should contact
the Office of Student Services at Student.Services@uopeople.edu.
Children's Online Privacy Protection Act
Although neither this website nor any of the University’s services are intended for children under
13 years of age, the University complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998
(“COPPA”) and does not knowingly collect any personal information online from children under
the age of 13.
Use of Cookies
The UoPeople Website may use "cookies", subject to your consent if you are a resident of the
European Union or are subject to GDPR, to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie
is a small data file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. The purpose of a cookie
is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize
Website pages, or apply for admission to UoPeople, a cookie helps the University recall your
specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal
information, such as your name and mailing address. When you return to the Website, the
information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can more easily use the UoPeople
features.
                                                     7

Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are
uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the
cookie to you.
By using the Website, its related websites and other services, you hereby agree to the use of
cookies as described herein. Note that most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you
can usually modify your browser settings to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline
cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Website.
Google Analytics
The University uses Google Analytics to collect information about use of the Website. The
University uses the data it receives from Google Analytics to improve the Website, and does not
combine the IP address collected by Google Analytics with your name or other identifying
information that you may enter on the Website. UoPeople cannot control Google’s use of the
information it gathers; however, Google's right to use and share information collected by Google
Analytics about your visits to the UoPeople Website is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of
Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on
return visits to this site by deleting its cookie or disabling cookies on your browser.
Your California Privacy Rights and Do Not Track Notices
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of a company who are California
residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personally identifiable
information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please
send an email to info@uopeople.edu. Please note that the University is only required to respond
to one request per customer each year.
Note that the University does not respond to “Do Not Track” signals.
The Microsoft CRM
The University’s Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system is hosted by Microsoft. There
is a seamless transition from the University’s main website to the CRM. You enter the CRM every
time you work on your application to the University or otherwise log in to the Student Portal. The
CRM processes and maintains all UoPeople applications, student records such as course
registration history and grades, and data related to payment history such as invoices and tracking
numbers. Note that the CRM does not store any of your personal bank account or PayPal
information.
Microsoft is not allowed to use your personally identifiable information other than for the
provision of services to the University or as otherwise permitted by law. For more information
about the Microsoft Dynamics CRM, you can review the security and privacy pages at the
Microsoft Dynamics CRM Trust Center and the Microsoft Privacy & Cookies page.
The Moodle Learning Platform
                                                     8

All of the University’s courses, classroom discussions, assignments, testing, the academic advising
messages system, and student and faculty forums are conducted through Moodle, an open-
source learning platform.
There is a seamless transition from UoPeople’s main website to the University’s Moodle platform.
No one outside the UoPeople community is permitted to access the UoPeople Moodle platform.
However, the UoPeople Moodle site administrators have access to nearly everything in the
system and certain private information is also accessible by other UoPeople students, faculty and
staff:
     1. UoPeople profile page. Every UoPeople student has a profile page in Moodle, which
         contains their first and last name, email address (optional), profile picture (optional) and
         description (optional). This information is visible to classmates for each course in which a
         student is enrolled, and to all students, faculty and staff through the Academic Advising
         Virtual Office. UoPeople profile pages are NOT available to the general public.
     2. UoPeople discussion forums. Since UoPeople is based on the peer-learning model, the
         University makes great use of discussion forums in its courses. Anything posted in a
         discussion forum is visible to the instructor and to all students enrolled in that course. For
         large classes that are divided into groups, only members of your group can see your
         posts. Your posts will include your full name and profile picture if you have chosen to
         upload it to the system.
     3. UoPeople peer-assessed assignments. All assignments assessed by other students in a
         particular course are submitted anonymously. Unless you put your name on your peer-
         assessed assignment, which is not a requirement, only instructors and administrators will
         be able to see who has evaluated your assignment.
     4. Private messaging system. Only the sender and receiver can view the content of
         messages sent through the Moodle privacy messaging system.
If you withdraw from the University, your account will be disabled and will no longer visible to
students and instructors. Old and inactive accounts are usually deleted after four years of nonuse.
Note that if you choose to create a public profile on the moodle.org or moodle.net sites, which
are outside the UoPeople Moodle platform, your information may become public and the Moodle
Privacy Policy shall apply.
The UoPeople Yammer Enterprise Network
UoPeople's Yammer Enterprise Network provides a collaborative environment for UoPeople
students, faculty, alumni, staff and volunteers from throughout the globe (“UoPeople
Community”) to connect and share meaningful information. Note that there is a seamless
transition from UoPeople’s main website to the University’s Yammer Network.
                                                    9

By enrolling in UoPeople’s Yammer Network, you understand and agree that your personal profile
and any content you post will be visible to other members of the UoPeople Community and to
anyone outside the community who manages to log in to the UoPeople Yammer Network.
Confidential student information and other sensitive or private content should not be posted on
the Yammer Network.
Although UoPeople administrators monitor all posts and comments to the UoPeople Yammer
Network, you are ultimately responsible for the content you post and UoPeople has a right and
obligation to report any user who posts illegal content and threats of violence to the authorities.
Prior to enrollment in the UoPeople Yammer Enterprise Network, users should review Microsoft’s
Yammer Privacy Statement and UoPeople’s Yammer Terms of Use.
Third Party Websites, Cookies and Privacy Policies
Certain pages of the Website may contain links to websites that are not controlled by the
University. Third-party cookies may be set by websites such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube,
Google Plus and other social media outlets or websites for which UoPeople may implement
plugins. UoPeople may permit other companies to place cookies and use cookies according to the
university policies and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Third-party Providers
In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information
to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us. However,
certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction
processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to
provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.
For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand
the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers. In particular,
remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different
jurisdiction than either you or us. So, if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the
services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws
of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located. For example, if you
are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the
United States, then your PII used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure
under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.
Once you leave our Website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no
longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our Website’s Terms of Service.
Third-party Links
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or Services on our
Website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore
have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless,
we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
                                                   10

Age of Consent
By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state, province or
country of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state, province or country of
residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this
site.
Retaining and Deleting PII
This Section 4 sets out our data retention policies and procedures, which are designed to help
ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of
personal data.
We will retain and delete your personal data as follows:
PII will be retained for 25 years following the point of first contact with the University at the end
of which period it will be deleted from our systems.
Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Privacy Policy, we may retain your PII where such
retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order
to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
Third-party cookies are not governed by this Privacy Policy. The University does not control and is
not responsible for the privacy policies or other content on websites other than the Website,
including websites linked to from the Website, or for the use of personally identifiable
information that you may submit to any of those websites. The University encourages you to
review the privacy policies of those third-party websites directly so that you can understand how
those websites collect, use and share your information.
Changes to this Policy
This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. Modifications will be denoted by the
“updated” notice at the top of this page. Your submission of personally identifiable information to
the Website following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes acceptance of
those changes. The University encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be
informed of its policies respecting your personally identifiable information. By continuing to
access the Website after notice of modifications have been published, you signify your agreement
to be bound by the updated terms.
Compliance with this Policy
The University regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions
regarding this Privacy Policy, or believe that the University has not adhered to any of its terms,
please contact the University at support@uopeople.edu.
                                                    11
